hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
in this session we are going to discuss
about the log viewer how you can view
your logs in Tosca commander and how you
can monitor them during the execution of
your test cases
now many a times you will face different
issues in Tosca and apart from the error
information which is provided either in
the scratch book or in the execution
logs there is also a log viewer which
provides you with complete or detailed
logs of what is happening with respect
to your execution and if there are any
errors or any issues you can easily
debug them using this log viewer
so let's look at how we can start this
log viewer and what are the different
options and how you can monitor your
logs using this log viewer application
so this particular log viewer
application is present in the commander
home directory and also in the t-box
home directory so we can start this by
directly going into that particular
directory and launching the exe we can
also launch it using the command line
tool
so uh if now I go here I am already in
my Tosca Commander uh home directory so
this is the Tosca Commander home
directory and here you will see uh there
is the log viewer okay so it's an exe
application
um so I can directly double click on it
and it will start the log viewer
application right here
it is also present in the teebox home
directory as I said earlier so you can
start it from there as well
now coming to uh the different options
which are present in this particular log
viewer application so the first option
is
um what kind of log level values will be
displayed okay so you can choose between
all these different logs
um So currently you can see it is off
which means it is not displaying any
logs but you can also choose uh to show
only the errors or the warnings or just
the information level logs or you can
choose to display all the logs so that's
also possible
the next option is display mode
um so here there are two options one is
the console mode and one is the file
mode so in the file mode it will only
show where the logs are being captured
and you can see uh this is the log file
which has been generated here okay by
default it will be stored in this
particular folders
and then this is the console mode where
you can view your logs in the console
itself
next is the files okay so again it is
showing you the different files which
have been created so this is the log
file and this is also the diagnostic
login.txt so I can directly go into
these uh different logs files okay so
these are the log files which have been
generated
then coming to the next option is the
clear option so if I click on clear it
will clear the logs on the console
I can save the logs separately okay if I
want to save the log events to a
different file I can do that okay so it
will store it in that file
then there is also a chrome Trace option
so we can use this Chrome test option to
basically store it into a Json file and
then we can use this file with the
Google Chrome's tracing event profiling
tool so so that we can even debug much
better with our respect to the Chrome's
up profiling tool
okay
um then uh this two options is for
navigating between different errors so
if you have got multiple errors you can
go to the next error or you can come
back to the previous error you can also
do a search using this find option so if
you want to search in your logs uh with
respect to something then you can easily
use this you can also use the regex and
previous and next option to go through
your search results
so these are all the different options
uh which you can see here right now if I
go ahead and start my Tosca Commander
okay
so here if I'm going into one of my box
pieces
and we will also keep the log viewer
handy here
so as you can see currently I have
selected all logs right so it is logging
everything into this particular console
so as soon as I started my Tosca
Commander you can see a lot of different
log events which have triggered in this
particular log viewer okay
now if I go ahead and execute some test
case like this login test case so I'll
go ahead and run this in scratchbook and
you will see lot of log events which
will be now triggering in this uh
console right so there is the debug log
level that is the info log level
um and then it is going to log
everything what your execution is doing
with respect to Tosca Commander the
different components and a lot of other
things okay some of the things uh may
not be understood by us but you don't
need to understand everything which is
being logged into this login log viewer
it will be mostly used for debugging
purpose right so if there is some
unusual behavior with Tosca Commander or
there is some error which you are not
able to get through or you don't find
any solution then maybe you can debug
something from this log viewer which
will show you some technical issue maybe
uh like this sending transaction to the
server field right but it was not
related to my test case
so um I can even change this uh log
level to only error so that I just see
the errors in my log viewer instead of
everything
so depends on how you want to set the
log level
but it's a very useful tool if you are
facing any issues which you are not able
to resolve using the usual logs which
are displayed in your execution or in a
scratch book but apart from that there
are lots of configuration issues which
you might face while configuring
different components of Tosca so there
could be lots of issues which could be
resolved by just looking at the log
viewer and maybe you can also provide
this to your technical team or the Tosca
support team so that they can help you
further
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments if you like this
video then please subscribe to our
Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video